

■ hello@hershnagpal.com | 🌴 hershnagpal.com | 🖸 hershnagpal | 🛅 hershnagpal

I'm a software engineer currently working in web and mobile development. As an engineer, I strive to maintain equity, safety, and forward thinking within my teams and most importantly, myself. I use multidisciplinary experiences to create a team environment where its engineers can grow.

Skills

Mobile Development Swift (SwiftUI, UIKit, Combine, XCTest), C# (Xamarin, .NET, Xamarin Forms)

Web Development TypeScript/JavaScript (React, Redux, Node), CSS (SCSS, Styled-Components) HTML, JSX

Other Software Java, Python, C++, AWS, (EC2, S3, CloudFormation, CodeBuild, CodePipeline)

Experience

DraftKings Remote, Boston, MA

Aug 2022 - Jun 2023

MOBILE APP ENGINEER

- Skills Utilized: C#, Xamarin, Swift, SwiftUI, Combine, .NET, iOS and Android Development
- Released the Player Page, Player Stats and News, and College Navigation features to the Xamarin Android and iOS DraftKings Sportsbook app
- · Refactored several app pages, including Event and League pages, to ensure peak performance during the Super Bowl and March Madness events
- · Architected, implemented, and tested the Team Pages feature to the DraftKings iOS App using SwiftUI and Combine
- Transitioned the Legacy Xamarin application to a new Composable SwiftUI application through NuGet package binding

Posterity Remote, New York, NY

- FRONT-END SOFTWARE ENGINEER Feb 2022 - Jun 2022
- Skills Utilized: React, TypeScript, NextJS, Styled Components, CSS, Storybook, Entrepreneurship Implemented and tested the Posterity.life progressive web application using TypeScript and React
- Integrated Storybook to increase design accuracy of UI components and isolate UI testing
- · Created reusable components and layouts based on Figma designs to reduce codebase complexity and build time
- · Regression tested all new components and pages to ensure seamless integration with both the new PWA and legacy application

PayPal Remote, Boston, MA

IOS ENGINEER CO-OP / BRAND ARCHITECTURE INTERN

Jun 2021 - Dec 2021

Jan 2020 – Jun 2020

Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

- Skills Utilized: Swift, UIKit, Postman, XCode, Unit Testing, Market Research, Business Strategy, Competitive Analysis
- Implemented new localization-specific features and UI elements for the EU release of the PayPal Business Debit Card
- Refactored and modernized outdated client-side Swift code for iOS PayPal Card products
- Researched new markets, mapped competition, and developed product names for potential new product offerings with PayPal's Brand Architecture team
- Volunteered with The Network for Teaching Entrepreneurship to teach 6–12th grade students entrepreneurial skills and judge business ideas

Wayfair Boston, MA

• Skills Utilized: Swift, UIKit, Autolayout, GraphQL, UI Design, Mobile Development

- · Developed the "Product Details" page, "Related Product" carousels, and product image carousels for the Wayfair 2020 iOS redesign
- Architected and implemented pages on the Wayfair iOS App using Swift and GraphQL on Wayfair's Product Detail Page and Shopping Cart teams
- · Created "Related Items" page, "Frequently Bought Together" carousel, "Additional Information" menus, and image carousels on all product pages
- Collaborated with software and QA engineers to implement multitasking split-view on iPad throughout the Wayfair iOS App.
- · Volunteered to host charity events on behalf of Wayfair to raise funds for St. Jude's Children's Hospital

Broadridge Deer Park, NY

DEVOPS INTERN • Skills Utilized: DevOps, AWS (CloudFormation, S3, IAM, EC2), Javascript, UI Design, Groovy, Jenkins, Marketing, Public Speaking

- · Constructed the foundations of an automated, cloud-based DevOps architecture to decrease the spin-up time of Broadridge Digital B2B products
- Optimized AWS microservice suite to reduce costs by 90% compared to the current on-premise solution
- · Designed a Broadridge online digital investor resource mobile app, which would massively reduce printing and mailing costs

Projects

IOS ENGINEER CO-OP

Egyptian Rat-Screw Carrot Wolf Hershnagpal.com **WayMovies**

An iOS version of my favorite card game, released to the App Store, written in Swift using SwiftUI and Combine

A Rogue-like game written in functional JavaScript using Redux for state management and Storybook for UI Testing My personal website written in functional TypeScript with Styled Components and Storybook, using AWS Amplify for CI/CD

An iOS app that allows browsing, searching, and saving movies, powered by TMDB. Written in Swift using UIKit and Autolayout An online checkers site where you can play against your friends or an Al player. Made using Java, Freemarker, and Spark

An RIT Sponsored startup for whom I created the MVP web application in React and Node, with MongoDB and Twilio integration

Education

Web Checkers

FiTR SKills

Rochester Institute of Technology

B.S. IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING, MINORS IN COMMUNICATION AND PSYCHOLOGY

2023 HERSH NAGPAL RESUME